<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Educate</string>
    <string name="hinttxt">Not case sensitive.</string>

    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="action_downloadall">Download All</string>
    <string name="action_resetDL">Reset DL</string>
    <string name="action_Help">Help</string>
    <string name="help_string_1">In the settings menu, you will be given the option to reset the download information for any of the subjects. <b>The download information is information regarding whether or not a file has been downloaded and an alert dialog box will pop up whenever a previously downloaded file is going to be downloaded again. Resetting the download information for a file means that whether or not you have downloaded that specific file already will be forgotten, allowing you to re-download files with 1 click once again.</b></string>
    <string name="help_string_2">In the "Reset Options" part of the menu, you will be able to reset download data for an entire subject, saving you the time from manually going through each activity and resetting the download information. </string>
    <string name="help_string_3">Below the reset option is the download options, which allows you to choose whether or not you will only download files with a WiFi connection.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_test_activity">test activity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_algebra_1">Algebra 1</string>
    <string name="title_activity_algebra_1__equation__with__variables">Equation With Variables</string>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_algebra_1__variables">Variables</string>
    <string name ="havingtrouble"><b>Having trouble getting answers?</b>\n\nWhat will frequently happen in math is that you will be unsure whether or not you’re doing a problem right or whether or not you have arrived at the right answer. This uncertainty can be incredibly frustrating to deal with, especially when you’re dealing with it for several problems rather than one. While it is not always to obtain perfect answers single-handedly or from someone else, the knowledge on how to maximize your chances of finding the correct answers can be obtained.\n\nWhen confronted with uncertainty, the first obvious thing to do is to google it. Type up the problem word for word, plug it into google, and see what you get. Plugging in the problem word for word is more likely to work for non-word problems, so for word problems a different approach must be taken. For word problems, you can either take a part of the word problem and google it or plug in the entire problem without any numbers. You will rarely get answers for the same exact problem with Google, but you will most likely end up getting information about nearly the exact same problem with different numbers.\n\nAnother good alternative to Google is WolframAlpha. While WolframAlpha will not be of help for word problems, if you are able to strip the problem down to a mathematical form (like an equation), then WolframAlpha can probably get you the answer. In addition to being able to provide information on equations, WolframAlpha allows you to query certain properties of an equation.\n\nExample:
    </string>
    <string name = "alg1_vars"><b>Variables</b>\nA variable is a letter that represents a number and the value of this number is either:\n-Unknown\n-Varying\n\nExample for a case of a variable representing an unknown number:\nx + 5 = 7\nWhat this equation means is stating is something plus 5 is equal to 7. Immediately, we do not know what x is; it is an unknown as far as we can tell.\n\nExample for a case of a variable representing a varying number:\nLet’s say you’re working as a waiter/waitress, and you make $80 a day. As a waiter/waitress, you also receive tips, so it’s more than likely that you will make more than just $80 a day. The actual amount of money you will make will be:\n\n$80 + t, where t represents the money you are making from tips\n\nBecause the amount of money you will obtain from tips varies, we cannot represent it as a solid number such at 5 or 10.\n\nIf you have obtained $20 on tips on Monday, then you have made $100 (80 base + 20 in tips) for the day; however, on Tuesday, if you have obtained $40 in tips, then you have made $120 (80 base + 40 in tips) for the day. As we can clearly see, the amount of money obtained in tips varies, which affects our quantity of daily wages.\n\nThe most common letter we will use to represent a variable is x, which is incredibly similar to the multiplication sign. Due to how x and the multiplication sign are indistinguishable, we will use * (an asterisk) to represent multiplication.\n\nSo instead of writing: 3 x 5 = 15\nWe will now write it as: 3 * 5 = 15</string>
    <string name="title_activity_algebra_1__pemdas">PEMDAS</string>
    <string name = "alg1_EWV"><b>Evaluating Equations with Variables</b>\n<b>A local fair is opening soon, and you would like to buy tickets to it for you and friends. The price for tickets is given by this following expression:\n2 + 5x, where x is the number of tickets that you want to buy.\n\nHow much does it cost to buy 1 ticket? 3 tickets? 5 tickets? 10 tickets?</b>\n\nAs the problem states, x is the number of tickets that you would want to buy, meaning that we will replace our variable x with the number of tickets we want to buy.\n\nFor 1:\nSubstituting 1 for x: 2 + 5(1)\nReplace 5 * 1 with its product: 2 + 5\nAdd the remaining 2 numbers together: 7 <b>(There’s nothing else we can do, so we’re done!)</b>\n\nFor 3:\nSubstituting 3 for x: 2 + 5(3)\nReplace 5 * 3 with its product: 2 + 15\nAdd the remaining 2 numbers together: 	17 <b>(There’s nothing else we can do, so we’re done!)</b>\n\nFor 5:\nSubstituting 1 for x: 2 + 5(5)\nReplace 5 * 5 with its product: 2 + 25\nAdd the remaining 2 numbers together: 	27 <b>(There’s nothing else we can do, so we’re done!)</b>\n\nFor 10:\nSubstituting 10 for x: 2 + 5(10)\nReplace 5 * 10 with its product: 	2 + 50\nAdd the remaining 2 numbers together: 52<b>(There’s nothing else we can do, so we’re done!)</b></string>
    <string name = "alg1_PEMDAS"><b>PEMDAS</b>\n\nOften times in Algebra I and beyond, you will encounter an equation that looks like this:\n3 * 5 + 6 – 3 / 3\nAnd you will be told to evaluate what number this is. Naturally, you will evaluate it going from left to right, so your work will look like:\n<b>3 * 5</b> + 6 – 3 / 3 =\n<b>15 + 6</b> - 3 / 3 =\n<b>21 – 3</b> / 3 =\n<b>18 / 3</b> =\n<b>6</b>\n\nAlthough it is natural for you to proceed with solving the equation this way, you are shocked to find out that your answer is wrong. Why?\n\nIn order to solve the issue of how to proceed with complex math equations, an order of operations was established, telling people exactly what operation they should do first when faced with an equation containing numerous different operations. The most common one that is used (and the one we will be using) is PEMDAS.\n\nPEMDAS is an abbreviated form of the order of operations of Parenthesis Exponents Multiplication Addition Subtraction. What this tells us to do is:\n(NOTE: these steps must be done in the sequence given. If there is nothing that we can do on a step, we can then skip to the next step)\n-Apply PEMDAS to items in parenthesis first\n-Then simplify any number with exponents next if there are no more quantities in parenthesis to solve for\n- Once we are done with exponents, then we multiply\n-When there is nothing left to multiply, then we divide:\n-After we have done the above four things, we add whatever numbers need to be added:\n-Finally, we do our subtraction\n\nNOTES:\n-If you have troubling remembering PEMDAS, you can try memorizing it as an acronym for Please Excuse My Dear Aunt Sally\n-For repeats of the same operation (including separate quantities in parenthesis that are side by side but not incased in one another), we go from left to right. PEMDAS gives the order to do different operations, not the order to do several of the exact same ones.\nExample: 2 + 7 + 3 + 4 = 9 + 3 + 4 => 12 + 4 => 16\n-If we are unable to do something at any given step, we skip to the next one. If we are already at the end, then we are done!\n-If you are faced with an equation with multiple quantities in parenthesis and don’t know where to start, find the rightmost “(“. Then apply PEMDAS to the quantity encased inside of it, and repeat this procedure until there are no more quantities in parenthesis left.\n\nExample:\nWhat is (6 + 3) * 2 / 3 – 5 + 8?\n<b>(6 + 3)</b> * 2 / 3 – 5 + 8 =\n<b>9 * 2</b> / 3 – 5 + 8 =\n<b>18 / 3</b> – 5 + 8 =\n6 <b>- 5 + 8</b> =\n<b>6 + 3</b> =\n<b>9</b>\nBecause there are no usages of exponents in this expression, we skip E and go directly to M\n\nAnother example:\nWhat is (6 * 3 + 5<sup>2</sup> – 6) + 4<sup>2</sup> – 8 + 6\n-The first thing to notice is that there are numerous operations in the parenthesis, so we apply PEMDAS to simplify 6 * 3 + 5<sup>2</sup> – 6 first.\n6 * 3 + <b>5<sup>2</sup></b> – 6 =\n<b>6 * 3</b> + 25 – 6 =\n<b>18 + 25</b> – 6 =\n<b>43 – 6</b> =\n<b>37</b>\n-We skipped P and D above since there were no parentheses or division in this equation.\n-Now we replace (6 * 3 + 52 – 6) with 37, giving us: 37 + 4<sup>2</sup> – 8 + 6\n37 + <b>4<sup>2</sup></b> – 8 + 6 =\n<b>37 + 16</b> – 8 + 6 =\n53 <b>- 8 + 6</b> =\n<b>53 – 2</b> =\n<b>51</b> (Final Answer)\n-We skipped P, D, and M above since there were no more parentheses, no division symbols, and no multiplication symbols in the equation.\n\nChained-Parenthesis Example:\nWhat is (63 – 43 + (18 * 4 + 12) – 15) + 16 * 2 + 14?\n-Start by finding the rightmost “(“. As we can see, the rightmost “(“ is right before 18.\n-The part of the equation encased by this rightmost “(“ is 18 * 4 + 12, so we apply to PEMDAS to that, and replace (18 * 4 + 12) with our result.\n<b>18 * 4</b> + 12 = <b>72 + 12</b> = <b>84</b>\n-So now we have: (63 – 43 + 84 – 15) + 16 * 2 + 14\n-We still have part of the equation encased in parenthesis, but there are no more parentheses encased in it, so we only need to simply the quantity inside of it and replace that part of our equation with our result.\n63 <b>– 43 + 84</b> – 15 =\n<b>63 + 41</b> + 15 =\n<b>104 + 15</b> =\n<b>119</b>\n-Now we replace (63 – 43 + 84 – 15) with 119 and simplify the remaining part of the equation.\n119 + <b>16 * 2</b> + 14 =\n<b>119 + 32</b> + 14 =\n<b>151 + 14</b> =\n<b>165</b> (Final Answer)\n
    </string>
    <string name = "alg1_SOQ"><b>System of Equations</b>\n\nA system of equations is a set of two or more equations which share the same set of variables/unknowns. When we are solving a system of equations, we are trying to find the numerical values of the variables/unknowns in the system such that when we plug in those numbers, the left side of each equation will equal to the respective right side.\n\nFor example, if we’re given this system of equations:\nx + 2y = 3\n6x - y = 4\nIf we put in x = 1 and y = 2, then we end up with:\n3 = 3\n4 = 4\nThus x = 1 and y = 2 solves this system of equation.\n\nSo how do we solve a system of equations?\nThe first step we do in solving a system of equations is making sure that for all equations in the system, all variables and numbers are lined up. If they are not, then you must move around parts of each equation to ensure that it. You may rearrange the equations in whatever format you may please, as long as similar variables and numbers line up (x terms like up with x terms, y terms like up with y terms, 2 lines up with 6, etc.).\nFor example:\nx + 7y = 10\n2x - 5 =  y\nLet’s say we want the equations in the format where x and y are on the left side, with y being right after x, and all numbers will be on the right side of the equation. The first equation is already in this format, so we leave it alone. The second equation is not in this format, so we must re-arrange it so that it will be. We can start by removing from the right side by subtracting y from both sides.\n2x - 5 = y => 2x - 5 - y = 0\nAs we can see from the left side, we want y to right after y so we switch – 5 and – y.\n2x - 5 - y = 0 => 2x - y - 5 = 0\nWe want 5 to be on the right side now; as we can see on the left side, we are subtracting 5. Naturally in order to remove it, we must add 5 to both sides.\n2x - 5 - y = 0 => 2x - y = 5\nNow both variables are on the left side (with the y term being right after the x term) and all numbers on the right side.\nSo our system as of right now is:\nx + 7y = 10\n2x – y = 5\n\nThe next step is to eliminate x. We can do so by multiplying one of the equations by a number so that the x terms in both equations are exactly the same. If we look at our system of equations, we have: x and 2x as our respective x terms.\nSo, we can either:\n-Multiply equation #1 by 2.\n-Multiply equation #2 by ½. (Fractions are fairy nasty to deal with early on, so you want to always go for multiplying by a flat number for now).\nSince it’s easier to deal with whole numbers rather than fraction, we will multiply equation #1 by 2.\nOur system of equations is now:\n\n2x + 14y = 20\n2x – y = 5\n\nThe next step to remove the x term from the first equation by subtracting the second equation from it. Because we had previously scaled the equation such that they both have the same x term, by subtracting one equation from the other we remove the x term from the first equation. You can also subtract the first equation from the second; however when you are just starting to learn algebra, it’s much easier to have a set, unchanging process for solving these problems.\nAfter subtracting the second equation from the first, we get:\n<b>(2x + 14y) – (2x – y) = 15</b>\nWhen we simplify we get:\n<b>(2x + 14y) – 2x + y = 15\n14y + y = 15 (We have a positive 2x term – 2x, which is equal to 0!)\n15y = 15\ny = 1</b>\nWe now know that y = 1 is the solution for the y part of our system of equations. Then what do we do with it?\n\nWe now can plug y = 1 into any one of the 2 original equations, and then solve for x because <b>by plugging in the solution for y, we reduce the equation to a form where there’s only an x term and a number. By reformatting the equation to where there’s the x term on one side and the number on the other, we can divide both sides by the number x is being multiplied by (aka a constant) in order to obtain the x term.</b>\n\nSo let’s substitute the y term (swapping out the y variable for the number it represents) in both of the original equations and see what happens.\n\n<b>For original equation 1:</b>\ nx + 7y = 10 => <b>x + 7(1) = 10 => x + 7 = 10\nx + 7 – 7 = 10 – 7 (Remove 7 from the left side by subtracting 7 from both sides)\nx = 3</b>\n\n<b>For original equation 2:</b>\n2x – 5 = y => <b>2x – 5 = 1\n2x – 5 + 5 = 1 + 5 (Remove subtracting 5 from the left side by adding 5 to both sides)\n2x = 6\nx = 3 (Number in front of the x term is 2, so we divide both sides by 2 to remove it)</b>\n\nAs you can see plugging in y = 1 into both equations get us the same value for x. If you do not obtain the same values from plugging in the y value you obtained, then you have probably made an arithmetic error on at least 1 of the equations\n\nHuman error is natural, so it’s fine if you mess up on solving them; however, as you get more and more used to solving them, you will be making less and less human errors.\n\nWhen you have gotten to the step where you are subtracting 1 equation from another to solve for 1 variable, sometimes you will get an equation with no variables at all. This does not mean you have messed up; it simply means that the system of equations either has infinitely many solutions or no solutions at all.\n-If you end up with 0 = 0, then there are infinite solutions\n-If you end with 0 = some number, then there are no solutions</string>
    <string name="title_activity_havingtrouble">Getting Answers</string>
    <string name="title_activity_help">Help</string>
    <string name="title_activity_algebra_1__system__of__equations">System Of Equations</string>
    <string name="title_activity_algebra_1__balancing__equations">Balancing Equations</string>
    <string name="title_activity_search">Search Results</string>
</resources>
